<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Political Psychology Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Political Psychology Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Natural Selection and the Political Mind</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-09-26-week-2-natural-selection-and-the-political-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-09-26-week-2-natural-selection-and-the-political-mind/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this week’s blog, I look at decision making and the way in which cooperation occurs between two parties. The importance of cooperation can be traced through an evolutionary lens. According to Axelrod, “Many of the benefits sought by living things are disproportionately available to cooperating groups” (pg. 92). Axelrod is asserting that psychological traits favoring cooperation were favored through natural selection, indicating humans today should lean toward cooperation when possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Making Decisions</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-09-19-week-1-making-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-09-19-week-1-making-decisions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For this week’s post, I am looking at the relationship of perceived candidate competence and electoral success. The subjectivity of measuring competence illustrates how other variables may persist in an individual’s decision making process to ultimately determine competence. This idea can be defined as attribute substitution, in which a difficult question (such as defining competence) is substituted for an easier one. A method of substitution is evaluating a candidate’s competence based on their facial quality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
