<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Political Psychology Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Political Psychology Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 10: Emotional Arousal and Hot Cognition</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-11-21-week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-11-21-week-10/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This week’s blog looks at the impact of emotions on political behavior, such as anxiety and disgust. This blog replicates Clifford and Jerit’s (2018) study, which considers the effects of disgust and anxiety on political behavior. They consider how people react to public health threats, specifically trying to understand how anxiety and disgust play into one’s response and the likelihood of being an “informed, activate public” (Clifford and Jerit, 2018, pg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9: Intergroup Contact</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-11-14-week-9-intergroup-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-11-14-week-9-intergroup-contact/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: In this week’s blog post, I am examining the idea of intergroup contact within a society. This includes situations like public transportation, sports, and neighborhoods. With all societies becoming significantly more diverse, understanding the outcomes of this on individuals is imperative. Will intergroup contact create conflict or contact?
Conflict: sharing space causes negative attitudes and behaviors.
Contact: sharing space causes positive attitudes
This blog seeks to answer the question of whether contact with a member of an outgroup can change people’s perception of that group?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8: Symbolic Politics</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-11-05-week-8-symbolic-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-11-05-week-8-symbolic-politics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: This week’s blog post evaluates the presence of symbolic attitudes in the political sphere. Symbolic attitudes can be described as stable, constrained, and influential toward other people and objects (have power). One application of symbolic attitudes can be seen by Reny and Newman (2021), in which they evaluate how symbolic predispositions impact people’s reactions to the George Floyd protests. Specifically, the authors consider police favorability and people’s perception toward Black Americans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7: Gender and the World View</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-10-31-week-7-gender-and-the-world-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-10-31-week-7-gender-and-the-world-view/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: This week’s blog evaluates the impact of gender on political outcomes, specifically surrounding conflict and war. Through past weeks, I have introduced the idea of SDO (Social Dominance Theory) and evolutionary principles that carry to today’s decisions. These ideas are significant with regard to gender. We see that women are typically more liberal than men (lower SDO scores). Further, due to different reproductive strategies, men have an evolved trait that males power, in this case through political careers, for desirable than compared to women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: World View</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-10-24-week-6-world-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-10-24-week-6-world-view/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: This week’s blog looks into the idea if liberals and conservatives lead different live and consider different world viewss: “a person’s whole cognitive orientation toward the socialworld”. In past blogs, I have demonstrated how political polarization and partisanship is deeply entrenched in today’s society. For example, in week 4, I showed that conservatives tend to have higher SDO scores, indicating their preferences for hierarchy. I am interested in analyzing how these beliefs go beyond the political sphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: The Political Psychology of Trump Indictment</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-10-17-week-5-the-political-psychology-of-trump-indictment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-10-17-week-5-the-political-psychology-of-trump-indictment/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: This week’s blog post considers the public opinion around the Trump indictments. Former President Trump was charged with 91 crimes, two being federal indictments, one in New York, and one in Georgia. These indictments have significance in two ways: he is the first former President to be charged with state or federal crimes, and these trials will be ongoing during the presidential campaign (Lecture (10/11), slide 5).
In this blog, I consider two behaviors voters can express.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Hierarchies</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-10-05-week-4-hierarchies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-10-05-week-4-hierarchies/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This week’s blog post considers the role of hierarchies and the idea of social dominance theory. Social dominance orientation (SDO) refers to the “general support for the domination of certain socially constructed groups over other socially constructed groups, regardless of the manner in which these groups are defined” (Sidanious, pg. 61). These groups can greatly vary including different demographic characteristics and belief systems, such as political orientation.
The main question that drives this blog post is to what degree can vote choice be as a function of SDO and other variables of interest?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Groups and Identities</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-10-02-week-3-groups-and-identities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-10-02-week-3-groups-and-identities/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: This week’s blog post considers the role of groups and identities in politics, specifically around party affiliation and the impacts of polarization. The study outlined in the blog serves as a replication of Iyengar, Sood, and Lelkes (2012) study. They seek to find the “proportion upset, displeased, or unhappy, if progeny married someone from another party.” To replicate this study, our class took a survey asking their happiness level (very unhappy to very happy) if their child married a Republican and, similarly, if they married a democrat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Natural Selection and the Political Mind</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-09-26-week-2-natural-selection-and-the-political-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-09-26-week-2-natural-selection-and-the-political-mind/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this week’s blog, I look at decision making and the way in which cooperation occurs between two parties. The importance of cooperation can be traced through an evolutionary lens. According to Axelrod, “Many of the benefits sought by living things are disproportionately available to cooperating groups” (pg. 92). Axelrod is asserting that psychological traits favoring cooperation were favored through natural selection, indicating humans today should lean toward cooperation when possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Making Decisions</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-09-19-week-1-making-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-09-19-week-1-making-decisions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For this week’s post, I am looking at the relationship of perceived candidate competence and electoral success. The subjectivity of measuring competence illustrates how other variables may persist in an individual’s decision making process to ultimately determine competence. This idea can be defined as attribute substitution, in which a difficult question (such as defining competence) is substituted for an easier one. A method of substitution is evaluating a candidate’s competence based on their facial quality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
