<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Political Psychology Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Political Psychology Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Hierarchies</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-10-05-week-4-hierarchies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-10-05-week-4-hierarchies/</guid>
      <description>add qualtrics photo Introduction: Data: The data used in this blog is a condensed version of survey conducted and generated by Data for Progress](https://wthh.dataforprogress.org/get-the-data)) in 2018. The data includes 3,144 rows (individuals) and 15 columns. The variables are primarily categorical variables, measuring the individuals&amp;rsquo; position on different questions with political undertones. The data also includes demographic variables such as race, education, sex, and age. The variables used in this blog are included below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Groups and Identities</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-10-02-week-3-groups-and-identities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-10-02-week-3-groups-and-identities/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: This week’s blog post considers the role of groups and identities in politics, specifically around party affiliation and the impacts of polarization. The study outlined in the blog serves as a replication of Iyengar, Sood, and Lelkes (2012) study. They seek to find the “proportion upset, displeased, or unhappy, if progeny married someone from another party.” To replicate this study, our class took a survey asking their happiness level (very unhappy to very happy) if their child married a Republican and, similarly, if they married a democrat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Natural Selection and the Political Mind</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-09-26-week-2-natural-selection-and-the-political-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-09-26-week-2-natural-selection-and-the-political-mind/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this week’s blog, I look at decision making and the way in which cooperation occurs between two parties. The importance of cooperation can be traced through an evolutionary lens. According to Axelrod, “Many of the benefits sought by living things are disproportionately available to cooperating groups” (pg. 92). Axelrod is asserting that psychological traits favoring cooperation were favored through natural selection, indicating humans today should lean toward cooperation when possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Making Decisions</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/2023-09-19-week-1-making-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/2023-09-19-week-1-making-decisions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For this week’s post, I am looking at the relationship of perceived candidate competence and electoral success. The subjectivity of measuring competence illustrates how other variables may persist in an individual’s decision making process to ultimately determine competence. This idea can be defined as attribute substitution, in which a difficult question (such as defining competence) is substituted for an easier one. A method of substitution is evaluating a candidate’s competence based on their facial quality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
